<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Alexis Taugeron]]></title>
  <link href="http://ataugeron.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ataugeron.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-09T17:16:27+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://ataugeron.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Alexis Taugeron]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Offscreen: An Amazing Reading Experience]]></title>
    <link href="http://ataugeron.github.com/blog/2012/06/05/offscreen-an-amazing-reading-experience/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-05T16:35:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://ataugeron.github.com/blog/2012/06/05/offscreen-an-amazing-reading-experience</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The sun has set now. The clock in the top right corner of my screen is showing 22:59, and I&#8217;ve been head down in some UX work for too many hours today. It&#8217;s now time for me to turn off the devices. I take a couple of minutes to put my stuff in order and write down my priorities for tomorrow in a Moleskine, then head to the bedroom.</p>

<p>I&#8217;m now comfortably seated in my bed and it&#8217;s reading time. I&#8217;m excited. The reason: a newcomer on my nightstand that&#8217;s been occupying the last hour of my days for about a week now. No, it&#8217;s not the last tome of Game of Thrones. Nor is it the last Tim Ferriss 4-Hour-something best-seller. It&#8217;s just a magazine. A simple magazine I came across on a blog a few weeks ago, and decided to order to <em>check it out</em>.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://ataugeron.github.com/images/offscreen_cover.jpg" title="Offscreen Cover" ></p>

<!-- more -->


<p>The cover, soberly titled <strong>Offscreen</strong>, shows an elegantly furnished office where three artsy dudes (wearing a beret, obviously) seem to be discussing some important issues. When you turn this thick cover, the first thing that hits you is a strong and pleasant smell of wood and ink. Then, a foreword explains you what you are about to read: <em>A print magazine about pixel people</em>.</p>

<p>A quick look at the mag&#8217;s website gives us a slightly more detailed description:</p>

<blockquote><p>Offscreen is an &#8220;old-fashioned&#8221; magazine in high-quality print, exploring the life and work of people that create websites and apps. We want to tell the less obvious human stories of creativity, passion and hard work that hide behind every interface.</p><footer><strong>Offscreen</strong> <cite><a href='http://www.offscreenmag.com/about/'>www.offscreenmag.com/about/&hellip;</a></cite></footer></blockquote>


<p><img class="center" src="http://ataugeron.github.com/images/offscreen_ondesk.jpg" title="On the Desk Of" ></p>

<p>Now that I finished it, I can say this magazine was an <strong>amazing</strong> reading experience for me.</p>

<p>Offscreen is:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Gorgeous:</strong> Everything is thoughtfully designed, from the cover to the acknowledgments. High-quality paper, aesthetic typefaces, beautiful pictures, nothing has been neglected, not even the ads which are so neat and relevant that I spent more than a minute on each of the eight sponsors pages, and ended up trying one of their products. If you want to know more about the process of creating Offscreen, you can read an interview of the author <a href="http://ilovetypography.com/2012/05/10/offscreen-magazine-interview-kai-brach">here</a>.</li>
</ul>


<p><img class="center" src="http://ataugeron.github.com/images/offscreen_ads.jpg" title="Sponsors Pages" ></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Authentic:</strong> This magazine is <strong>not</strong> about how some ninja-coders cranked out an awesome website in their dorm and became billionaires the next day. It&#8217;s about the real, normal folks who craft with passion the websites and apps we use every day. It&#8217;s about their work, their careers, but also their personal lives. Where do they live? How does their schedule look like? What music do they listen? What are their hobbies? Where do they find inspiration?</li>
</ul>


<p><img class="center" src="http://ataugeron.github.com/images/offscreen_dayinlife.jpg" title="A Day in the Life Of" ></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Inspiring:</strong> I&#8217;m in a key period of my life. Freshly out of college, starting my own projects, trying to <em>figure out my next move</em>. The possibilities are infinite. Now, more than ever, I&#8217;m in need for role models to point me in the right direction. Earlier this year I read Steve Job&#8217;s biography. I found it fascinating, I have a lot of respect for what he&#8217;s done, but I can hardly take him as an example. I don&#8217;t want to sacrifice my health, my personal life, my family, to build a highly successful company. I don&#8217;t want to become a billionaire, have my private jet and yacht. No, what I need is real people I can actually identify with. Offscreen is full of them; people who are two, five, ten years ahead of me, who share similar interests with me, and live a balanced lifestyle I can totally picture myself living five years from now. Reading about their lives just inspired me <strong>a ton</strong>.</li>
</ul>


<p><img class="center" src="http://ataugeron.github.com/images/offscreen_interview.jpg" title="Interview of Andrew Wilkinson" ></p>

<p>After I finished the very last page and put the magazine back on my nightstand, I decided to:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>give it to someone I know will enjoy it as much as I did</p></li>
<li><p>order the issue n˚2</p></li>
<li><p>write this blog post to spread the word and hopefully convince a few people to <em>check it out</em></p></li>
</ul>


<p>So here you go: if you&#8217;re a creative person, a builder, a maker, if you&#8217;re curious about the lives of your peers, if you&#8217;re looking for a delightful reading experience, check out <a href="http://www.offscreenmag.com/">Offscreen</a>!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Between Stimulus and Response]]></title>
    <link href="http://ataugeron.github.com/blog/2012/02/27/between-stimulus-and-response/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-27T17:02:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://ataugeron.github.com/blog/2012/02/27/between-stimulus-and-response</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently finished the book <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0743269519/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=alexistaugero-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0743269519">The 7 Habits of Highly Effective People</a> , by Stephen R. Covey. If you’re interested in improving yourself and didn’t get to read this classic yet, I strongly recommend it. I didn’t find everything useful in the book, but I love the framework it provides. It’s both conceptually meaningful and practically actionable. It has helped me improve several aspects of my life. I won’t spoil you the whole book and tell you what the 7 Habits are, but I want to share with you one idea I loved in the first chapter.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>The first habit Covey presents is “Be Proactive”. In order to illustrate one of the ideas embodied in this concept, he tells us about the inspiring story of Viktor Frankl, an Austrian psychiatrist who survived the Holocaust. While suffering the horrors of the death camps, he learned a powerful lesson:</p>

<blockquote><p>One day, naked and alone in a small room, he began to become aware of what he later called “the last of the human freedoms” — the freedom his Nazi captors could not take away. They could control his entire environment, they could do what they wanted to his body, but Viktor Frankl himself was a self-aware being who could look as an observer at his very involvement. His basic identity was intact. He could decide within himself how all of this was going to affect him. Between what happened to him, or the stimulus, and his response to it, was his freedom or power to choose that response.</p><footer><strong>Stephen R. Covey</strong> <cite><a href='http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0743269519/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&tag=alexistaugero-20&linkCode=as2&camp=1789&creative=390957&creativeASIN=0743269519'>The 7 Habits of Highly Effective People</a></cite></footer></blockquote>


<p>Viktor Frankl himself wrote:</p>

<blockquote><p>Everything can be taken from a man but one thing: the last of the human freedoms-to choose one&#8217;s attitude in any given set of circumstances, to choose one&#8217;s own way.</p><footer><strong>Viktor Frankl</strong> <cite><a href='http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0807014273/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&tag=alexistaugero-20&linkCode=as2&camp=1789&creative=390957&creativeASIN=0807014273'>Man&#8217;s Search for Meaning</a></cite></footer></blockquote>


<p><img class="center" src="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/f/fe/Viktor_Frankl2.jpg/220px-Viktor_Frankl2.jpg" title="Viktor Frankl" ></p>

<p>These sentences had a big impact on me. I’ve never been in a situation nearly as harsh as what Frankl lived, but I get my share of hassles, just like everyone else. Since that reading, I made a habit of taking a step back whenever something happens to me, and consciously decide how I am going to react, rather than letting the events dictate my mood. Easy to say, hard to do&#8230;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How I Learned to Type Really Fast with Less Effort]]></title>
    <link href="http://ataugeron.github.com/blog/2012/02/06/how-i-learned-to-type-really-fast-with-less-effort/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-06T10:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://ataugeron.github.com/blog/2012/02/06/how-i-learned-to-type-really-fast-with-less-effort</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As my <a href="http://10fastfingers.com/user/37311/">10fastfingers profile</a> can attest, my average typing speed in English is 90 wpm (words per minute). To give you some context, the world record is 216 wpm, an average typing speed is around 30-40 wpm, and jobs like secretary often require a typing speed around 50-80 wpm. (Source: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Words_per_minute">Wikipedia</a>)</p>

<p>How did I manage to reach this speed? The answer is simple: I switched to the Dvorak keyboard layout.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>For historical reasons, most people use the QWERTY layout. This layout was designed in the 1870s to put commonly used letter-pairs far from each other so as to prevent jams in old typewriters. If it made sense back then, it is now completely suboptimal with our modern keyboards. And yet, most people still use it, just because it’s there&#8230; There are two things wrong with this layout that purposely makes your fingers travel more over the keyboard. First, it makes you type slower. Second, it makes you more likely to get repetitive strain injuries like <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Carpal_tunnel_syndrome">carpal tunnel syndrome</a> (CTS).</p>

<p>In April 2011, a colleague introduced me to the Dvorak layout. He actually got CTS after years of programming, and this layout helped him solve this problem. The Dvorak layout, developed in the 1930s, is designed so that the most commonly used letters are on the middle row, where your fingers usually rest. Letters are arranged so as to alternate between each hand. It results in a very balanced and fluid way of typing, that requires much less fingers movements than the QWERTY layout. Typing in Dvorak is not only efficient, it’s enjoyable. That was enough to convince me to give it a try.</p>

<p>Here is how this layout looks like:</p>

<p><img src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_dv5nz9-JGWk/TTcN7HL6nRI/AAAAAAAAACo/RcuLgErk-js/s1600/dvorak.png" title="&#34;The Dvorak Keyboard Layout&#34;" alt="&#34;The Dvorak Keyboard Layout&#34;"></p>

<p>And here’s a video of someone typing in Dvorak. Look how little his fingers move:</p>

<iframe width="420" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/Ds98JcaGrLA" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>Making the switch was no easy task. The first week was a pain in the ass, but I was determined. In order to memorize the layout, I used the Mac keyboard viewer during the first two days. It then took me about three weeks to get back to my initial productivity. Ten months later, I’m still typing in Dvorak, and I love it! There’s no way I go back.</p>

<p>I’m glad I invested some time and efforts in learning this skill that not only allows me to type faster, but also makes me actually enjoy typing. As a side note, here’s a funny outcome I noticed: since I type in Dvorak but my physical keyboard is in QWERTY, the labels on the keys I press have nothing to do with what I actually type. That means nobody can spy over my shoulder to steal my passwords. Ah ah, who said I’m paranoid?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
